ALEXANDRE AH-CHAN

+614 34 700 416

alex ahchan@hotmail.com

2/11 Palmer street, Oakleigh 3166, Victoria, Melbourne, Australia.

Profile

I endeavour to join an interactive organisation that offers a constructive and interactive workplace, equipped to challenge my skills and facilitate interaction with customers and staff. I pride myself in my ability to adapt to evolving situations, learn from my various experiences, and continuously strive for improvement professionally and in my education.

Experience

Front of house manager, Bouchée café, Melbourne April 2013 to Present

I have been working as the manager of the Bouchée café, one of the busiest restaurant in Chadstone shopping centre, for five years. During this time, I have been promoted from food and beverage attendant, to supervisor, and lastly front of house manager.

Bouchée café is a high volume restaurant that serves between 50 to 60 kg of coffee on a weekly basis and up to 90kg to 120kg during the festive season. It can accomodate up to 125 patrons in one sitting and produces about 550 meals throughout a nine hour period (1 trading day) on a standard weekend day. It also provides catering services for international high-end retail shops such as Tiffany&co, Escada, Apple and Chadstone shopping centre management for VIP events.

Duties include but not limited to:

Staff

- Conducting interviews, trials and dismissal of employees as required
- Undertaking monthly reviews of employees to ensure skill development and high customer service outputs
- Facilitating training and education of employees to improve specific competencies as necessary
- Preparing a weekly roster

Financial Operations

- · Reconciling financial transactions at the end of each day
- Negotiating with suppliers regarding new products and price range
- Managing expenses and successfully working within an allocated budget
- Invoicing, quoting and supervising catering events

General Management

- Overseeing service and presentation of coffee, beverages and food to a high standard
- Front of house weekly stocktake and ordering
- Handling customer complaints with sensitivities and respect
- Ensuring high standards of occupational health and safety and hygiene are maintained
- Directing and assisting wait staff with restaurant floor tasks on busy days
- Preparing new seasonal menu and corresponding prices
- Updating and implementing new operational plans on a regular basis
- Resolving issues raised by the company directors in relation to the premises as well as relevant liquor licensing

Bar supervisor, Shine café, bar & lounge; Melbourne January 2012 - September 2013

My duties included assisting in the making of new cocktails menu, setting up the bar for functions and managing bar staff on busy nights. In addition, I was responsible for providing a weekly stocktake of bar products to the manager.

Supervisor, Bouchée café; Melbourne November 2011 - April 2013

Responsibilities included supervising the food and beverage attendant, as well as supporting the manager with his daily tasks. These included but were not limited to assisting in the making of new menu, following up with weekly cleaning schedule, training of new staff and stocktake.

Barista / food & beverage attendant / waiter, Bouchée café; Melbourne February 2011 - November 2011

I was involved in high volume coffee making, preparation and serving of savoury food, desserts and beverages. In addition to waitering, running and clearing of tables.

Assistant manager, Lotus snack; Mauritius November 2008 - March 2009

Lotus snack is a small family business. I was assisting the manager with the weekly stocktake/ordering, reconciling financial transactions at the end of each day and following up with payments to be made to suppliers.

Education

Institute of Hotel Management Australia

- -Diploma in Hospitality 2015
- -Certificate 4 in Commercial Cookery 2015

College du Saint Esprit

-Higher School Certificate (Cambridge) 2008

School of Electronics

-Basic Electronic Module 2005

Skills

Across my work experiences I have always endeavoured to establish new skills and grow my expertise. During my work managing Bouchée, I have advanced and diversified my responsibilities resulting in a strong work ethic and ability to multi-task. My experiences have fostered great professional and personal growth. Moving forward, I feel highly confident and motivated in my ability to furthermore expand my skill set and take the next step in my career. My range of highly developed skills and competencies include but are not limited to:

- Proficient communication with stakeholders
- Confident and collected when working under pressure
- Strong leadership and teamwork capabilities
- Proactive planning and decision making
- Efficient time management and high multi-tasking capacity
- Effective conflict resolution

Languages skills

English

French

References

Kelly Fisher previous manager at Bouchée café : +614 14 340 465

Luvv Luthra Head chef at Bouchée café: +614 74 907 638